Oh no.
Oo.
Oh. Oh, [music]
I feel
Heat. Heat.
Oo.
Oh.
Hey. Hey.
Heat. Heat. N.
Heat. Heat.
Well, thank you for coming to Movement Church. We hope you had
a wonderful time celebrating America. Are you ready to celebrate the Lord
this morning? Here we go. Come on.
[music]
Jesus [singing] is mine.
Oh, what a foraste [singing] of glory [music] divine.
Hear [singing] of salvation,
purchased of [music] God,
born of his spirit. [singing] Oh, I'm washed in his blood. Oh,
[music] said I can't stop singing. Oh, [singing] spirit of soul.
[music] I'm praising my savior all the day. for the table. [music]
I got a song and I'll sing it [singing] loud. My praise
is pouring out. My [music] praise is pouring out. And I will
dance in your freedom. Now you have brought me out. You have
brought me out. [music] Every
[music] [singing]
Jesus is mine.
Oh, what [singing] a full taste of glory [music] divine. >> Of salvation.
>> Of [singing] salvation.
Purchase [music] of God of his spirit, born of his [singing] spirit.
Oh, I'm watching his love. Oh, [music] I can't stop singing.
[music]
[singing] I'm praising my savior. [music] All day long, all day long.
I got a song and sing it out. Heat. Heat. [music]
[music]
You brought me out. I got a song. [singing]
[singing]
[music]
I got a song. [singing] My [music] greatest.
[music and singing]
[music] Oh, thank you, Lord. We're free. Amen.
God, if you're free, let's sing. Hey, here we go. Hey. Hey.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey. We thank you, Jesus.
From the sunset free. [music]
Oh, we thank you. [music] We thank [singing] you, Lord, for your
word. [music] Hey,
[music] your [singing] word is a lamp unto [music] my feet.
And your way is the [music] only [singing] way for me.
It's a narrow road, [singing and music] but the mercies are wide. Cuz you're
good on your promise.
Oh, it's a narrow [singing] road, [music] but then we'll lead life.
But I want to be honest, and I'll [singing] take you at
your [music] word. Said [singing] it out.
See how good it was. [music] finding [singing] your
I take you as [music and singing] oh
[music] you know the chaos will
[music]
I know
[singing] it in my
Narrow road that leads [music and singing] to life. We don't want to be
on it.
Narrow road the tide is high to [music] part in the water.
I want to [singing] take you as
said [music and singing] I believe. I see how [singing] good you are. [music]
I'll take [music] you as
it [music and singing]
see.
[singing and music]
I'll take you. [music and singing]
[music] I'll take you. All your promises are
[music] [singing]
your love will never [music and singing] give up. You say your grace is
always enough. You say your heart will never [music and singing] forget or forsake
me. Oh, you said I'm safe. You call me [music] yours.
You said my future full of your [music and singing] fail. So I know
that you'll never fail me. [music] You said your [singing] love
never give up. You said [music] your race is always enough. You
said your [music and singing] heart never forget for me. [music]
You said [singing] you [music] said my future
and you never [music and singing] so I know that you'll never [music] [singing]
[music] if you said it [singing] I'll leave it. I've seen [music]
how good it was. Yes, I have. >> [singing] [music]
>> I'll take you out.
[singing and music]
[singing] [music]
Heat. [music] Heat. [singing]
[music]
[singing]
>> [music]
>> I will take you [music and singing] by
the Lord praise. [music] Oh, we thank you, Jesus. Oh, we bless
your name, [music and singing] Jesus. Come on, church. Let's just lift our hands
and thank the Lord this morning for his goodness, for his promises.
[music] Oh, we thank you Lord. Oh, we thank you for your
promisees. [singing]
Because it is written, [music] you're my [singing] refuge and strength. Though
the earth may pass [music] away, will remain.
And it [music and singing] is written that you provide every [singing] need everywhere
[music] that you will lead. You will sustain.
You keep [music and singing] your promises.
[music and singing] Your goodness never ends. [music] From [singing] generation
to generation [music and singing] you keep your covenant.
[music] See your faithfulness. [singing] >> You see your faithfulness
>> from [singing] generation. >> From generation [music]
to generation. [singing]
[singing]
For it is written, [music] we're redeemed by [singing] your blood. All
the old has passed away. [music and singing] The new has come. For it
is written, [singing] it's now by power
by spirit [music and singing] of the living.
Oh, [music and singing] you keep your promises
for [music and singing] your goodness.
generation [music and singing] generation
to generation.
[music and singing]
[singing and music]
>> [music and singing] >> Oh, we thank you Lord. You are faithful God.
Oh, we [music and singing] thank you, Lord. Come on, let's thank you for
his faithfulness. Oh, we thank you. We will trust [singing] you and
[music] believe as it's rich and let it be. You alone will
be a firm [music and singing] foundation.
Lord, what you spoken is enough. [music and singing] And it's the crown we're
standing on. You are kind [singing] and we will [music] not be
shen.
Oh, we [music and singing] will trust you and believe. And as it's written,
let it be. [music] Cuz you alone [singing] will be a
[music] strong
[singing] [music]
[music and singing]
[music]
[singing] Heat. Heat. Heat. [music] [singing]
Yeah. Heat. [music] [singing]
[music] [singing]
Heat. Heat. Heat.
[music and singing]
Heat. [music] Heat. [singing]
[music]
>> [music] [singing]
>> You are you
[singing and music] Jesus.
Oh, we thank you, Lord. [singing] We thank Oh, we thank you,
Lord. Come [music] on, lift your hands and [singing] thank the Lord
this morning. Oh, we thank [music and singing] you Jesus.
Oh, we thank [singing] you Jesus. [music]
Oh, [singing] we [music] thank you Jesus.
Come on, thank him this [music] morning for his promises. They are
yes and [singing] amen. His word is final authority. So we thank
you for that, Father. We [music] thank you [singing] Lord. We thank
you Lord. >> Oh we thank you Lord. We [singing] thank you [music]
Lord.
>> Oh come on. We thank you Jesus. [singing] [music] >> We thank you
Lord. You're so faithful [singing] God. >> You're so faithful
Lord. [music] >> From generations. >> Oh [singing] we bless you Lord >> to generations.
We bless you, [music] Lord. [singing] We bless you, Jesus. He's such
a faithful God. [music] Oh, we worship you, Lord.
We bless [music and singing] your name.
And I'm going to [singing] hit it [music]
with the last name.
[music]
All [singing] the saints and angels [music] they bow
[singing] before your [music] throne.
>> [singing] >> All the elders [music] cast their crowns before [singing] the lamb
of God [music] and [singing] sing all the saints. All [music] the
saints and [singing] angels [music] that bow before [singing]
your throne.
>> [singing and music] >> All the elders cast their crowns [singing] before the lamb
of God and sing. [music] You are worthy [singing] of it all.
Lord, [music and singing] you're worthy of it all.
For [singing and music] from you are all things and to you are all
you deserve. >> You deserve the [music and singing] glory.
All the saints and angels
we sing [music and singing] all the saint and angels
they bow [singing and music] before your throne. Oh,
all [singing] the [music] elders cast their crowns before the lamb
[music] of God and [singing] sing. Lord, you're worthy [music] of it
all. He's worthy. Yes, he is, Lord. [music] You are worthy [singing]
of it all.
Yes, you are. [music] [singing] from you are
[singing] you [music] deserve glory
[singing] [music] you
[singing] see [music]
[singing]
you Heat. Heat. Heat. [music]
[music]
Yeah. Heat. [music] [singing]
[music and singing]
Heat. [music]
[singing] [music]
you
are [music] so clear right now. We lift our hands, we lift
our voices, and we worship you, Jesus. [music] Oh, there's a night
like you, Lord. There's a man like you, Lord.
[music and singing]
Oh, we [music and singing] bless your name. We bless your name. Oh, [music]
[singing]
and we sing day and [music and singing] night, night and day, their worship
for us. [music] Day and night, [singing] night and day, their worship.
Day and night. [music] Sing it out. We sing day and night.
Heat. Heat. [music and singing]
[singing]
Heat. [music] Heat. [singing]
[music and singing]
Yeah.
Heat. [music]
[music and singing]
[music] [singing] Oh, [music] you
[singing]
[music] [singing]
[music]
[music] Heat. [singing]
Heat.
[music and singing]
Yeah. [music and singing] Heat.
[music] [singing]
Yeah. [music] Heat.
[music]
[music] Oh,
[singing]
[music]
[music] Jesus.
I
[music] exalt [singing] thee. Exalt the Lord. You are highly [music] exalt.
[singing]
>> I exalt. >> Come on. Let's lift that up this [music] morning. Lord,
[singing] >> I exalt thee. Oh. [music]
>> Oh, [singing] we your name. We exalt you Jesus name. [music]
>> I [singing] exalt thee. >> Oh exalt you Jesus.
>> I [singing] exalt [music] thee >> over everything. Lord
I [singing] exalt thee. [music] >> Oh [singing]
[music] cuz you're worthy of it all. Lord, you're [music and singing] worthy of
it all. We tell him this morning, you're worthy. You're worthy of
it all. [music and singing]
>> For from [music and singing] you are all things and to you are all
things. >> You deserve >> You deserve the glory. [music and singing] You're worthy of it
all. Lord, >> you are worthy [singing] of [music] it all.
>> So worthy, Jes. >> You are worthy of it all. [music] >> So worthy
[singing] of our praise. For from you are all things. [singing] And
to [music] you, >> from you, far from you [singing] are all things.
And [music] to you are all [singing] for from you are all
[music] things and to you are all things. You [music and singing] deserve the
glory.
[singing] [music]
[singing]
[music]
We [singing] [music] bless your name. We bless.
>> We bless your [singing] name. We bless.
[music] >> Oh, we worship you, Jesus. [singing]
[music] >> Lord, we praise you. >> We praise you. >> Worthy of it all.
All glory is yours, Lord. [music] You are so worthy. Thank you
Lord every day for this amazing country [music] you put us in.
Thank you Lord for giving us a place where we can freely
worship you, where we can put you in your rightful place above
all things because you are the only [music] one one worthy to
be put above all things. Thank you God. You know when I
was praying on what God wanted me to talk about during this
moment, he led me to Isaiah 53. And if you don't know
that chapter, it's all about a coming Messiah and what he was
going to have to suffer with. He was going to be pierced
for our transgressions. He was going to be crushed for our iniquities.
He was going to die for our sins. It's talking about Jesus.
It's all [music] about Jesus. And you know, I was thinking, what
what is it about this specific chapter that he wants me to
talk about? We know about Jesus's love and how he died for
us, how he gave himself up for us. But the last verse
in that chapter [music] is what hit me. The last one is
talking about how he makes intercessions for the transgressors. That was us.
We were the ones [music] transgressing against him. And so he makes
intercessions for us. But what does that mean? Intercessions is kind of
a big silly word that a lot of us don't really use.
But if you look at the Greek translation when that old [music]
testament was translated to the new the Greek that word is what
we would kind of use for like a defense lawyer. The Greeks
are big on law. And so the transgressor is saying that Jesus
or I mean intercession is saying that Jesus is going to speak
on your behalf. He's gonna speak to God and be like, "You
know what? This man has made mistakes, but don't worry [music] about
that. He's a good man." You know why? Because he points to
his side. He shows you his hands because his sin was already
paid for. So the opposite side of that is the accuser. So
we all know the accuser. That's the enemy. And that is what
we would use for the word persecutor or prosecutor in our legalistic
mindset. So, he, the enemy, is trying to accuse us of all
of these things. He's trying to say, "You know what? You didn't
do this right. You didn't do that right. God, look at him.
Look at him. He made mistakes. You should send him to the
fiery lake. You should punish him. You should let me torment him."
And Jesus is like, "You know what? Bought and paid for. Bought
and paid for. I died for that man. So, his sins, everything
he's doing, it it doesn't matter anymore. Now, he doesn't need to
do that anymore. He should stop doing these things and follow me.
But I [music] paid for it, so it doesn't matter anymore. Don't
even look at him, Lord. Look at me. So that's what Jesus
is doing for us after he died on that cross. He bought
and paid for all of our sins [music] so that we don't
have to suffer the what the accuser thinks we need to suffer.
>> So right now, maybe something's being put on your heart that you
made a mistake. That's the accuser. He's trying to get into your
mind and tell you that you didn't do this right. You didn't
do that right. Remember, you have the perfect defense attorney. And he's
free. >> He's free. He's not going to cost you a dime. He
fought and paid for it. So, you don't have to live that
life. So, maybe right now you're at home with a stomach bug.
And the accuser is hitting you in your mind. You should be
at church right now. Don't worry about it. Jesus got you. >> He's
taking care of you. Don't listen to that accuser. You're listening right
now. We see you. We know you're here. So you don't have
to suffer that pain, that torment, that anguish that that accuser is
trying to bring on your life because you have the best defense
attorney that already bought and paid for any crime you may have
made, making or will make in the future, it is gone in
Jesus name. So I thank you, Father, every day that you sent
your son to die for our sins, to wash us clean in
his blood, to cover us with [music] his love, to protect us,
to speak on our behalf, to just be everything we could possibly
need. We love you so much, Lord. We thank you every day
in Jesus name. Amen. >> Amen. >> You be seated. Oh, happy birthday.
Happy America birthday. As my wife likes to say, happy 250. 250.
It's crazy. Oh, man. This is a been a very interesting time.
You know, we have this every year, Fourth of July, but this
is a big one. This is different. It's not because we had
a UFC fight at the White House. It's not because we had
some silly things happen. It feels like there's a tide turning that
people are starting to wake up to see that this is really
the greatest country that exists today and I think has ever existed
before. No country has been as free as us. Now we have
had mistakes. We have made you know mistakes in the past and
have a dark past but every country has made mistakes. We were
the first country to start to correct these mistakes to, you know,
I I heard something recently that the northern [music] colonies, even before
England signed a proclamation freeing slaves, the northern colonies of this United
States of America had already put it in their state constitutions that
slavery should be abandoned, should be abolished. So, we did it before
England did it. And England usually gets the the notoriety for being
the ones that abolish slavery first. Well, actually, a lot of the
states in America did it first. We weren't perfect, and it took
some of us a little bit longer to get there, but you
know, every state, every country at the time had slavery. You can't
take our past mistakes and hold it to us against us in
the future because this country [music] allows so much freedom. We have
so much more freedom and so much more, you know, [music] rights
for everybody, for women, for uh for all races, all genders. You
know, there's only two, but both of them have equal equal rights.
And so I I'm so grateful for this nation and just you
look at all the Europeans coming over here for the FIFA World
Cup and what they're they're saying is America is amazing. These people
are so nice. The food is great. You know, all these amazing
things. is a beautiful place, not like what the media tells us.
We've all thought this place is a bunch of horrible, mean people,
but that's not what this country is. That's not what it was
founded to be, and it's not what it is now. >> And so,
we have to stop listening to the noise and just open your
eyes to what you see. And right now, I see just a
room filled with all different kinds of people. people that are great,
people that are loved by Jesus that are not really any different
from one another. And it is amazing melting pot of what this
country really is. And so on this 250 birthday, I wasn't planning
on talking about this. The Holy Spirit just was bringing it out
of me. You know, I I just encourage you to stop listening
to the garbage that's trying to tear this down, this country down,
tear everybody apart, rip [music] us into these little factions. That's not
what this country is made to be. That's not what God wants
us to be because that's not what it's going to be like
in heaven. We're all going to be just one big loved group
of people that are going to love each other, love God, and
just be in perfect fellowship. And that's what we need to be
here every day. So, stop listening to the junk and just listen
to Jesus. >> And so, if this if this is your first time
here, I welcome you. This is an amazing place that I've had
been privileged to be with from the very first Bible study at
the pastor's house. And we've come a very long way and we
have a very long way to go. But if this is your
first time here, I welcome you to get this uh one of
these packets up at the front. It's got a little gift card
in it. It tells you a little bit more about the church.
And really what the goal here is is why it's called Movement
Church. It's to move you from where you are into where God
has called you to be. I was broken. I was lost. I
was hurting. And now through Jesus Christ. I am redeemed. I am
whole. I am so much better than I ever was. And I
thank in part to this church. This is an amazing church that
God is really working through. So, if this is your first time
here, get the the p the packet. You can fill out the
QR code. Uh well, you can scan the QR code and it'll
take you to a form that you can fill out. Just tells
us a little bit about you. Uh, we're not going to hound you
or anything, but um, you know what I really encourage you to
do is come back. Don't just go come one time. Come back
for a second time, maybe a third time or 40 or 50
times because you'll see the love. You'll see the power here because
this [music] place is filled with the Holy Spirit. >> And it is
is amazing place that can really change lives. So, if you need
something in your life to change, come back here and you'll find
it. I guarantee it. So, as you can kind of see, there's
a lot of open chairs here. It's not normally the case. There's,
you know, the enemy is trying to attack a lot of the
uh members of this church, and we come against that in the
name of Jesus. But usually, this place is very, very full. And
so, we need to go to the next step. We were first
at the the pastor's house. That filled up real quick. They really
wanted us to, you know, find something else. Then we went to
uh Mud Pies and Lullabies which was um a great little place
but we were ready to move out of that. Now we're here
and this place has been an amazing blessing for us but it's
not our final destination. So we have another step the next step
that we're going to we're getting land we're getting a building and
with that you know we are standing in faith because it's not
easy to to just automatically have that unless you know somebody here
has 20 30 acres of land that are willing to give. then
it's really easy. Um, praise the Lord. So, [music] every week we
say a confession about where we're going, about where we're heading. We're
standing in faith on the word of God, on the promises of
God that he's given our pastors, he's given this church that there
are going to be amazing things coming from this church. There already
have been, but [music] we've got so many more amazing things to
come. Just talk to the pastors for like three minutes and they'll
give you 47 ideas of what they're doing in the future. starting
Bible colleges. You know, we already started a school here. It's just
there's so much amazing things. So, I encourage you to say these
confessions with us in faith, boldly, confidently knowing that this is where
we're heading. It's not just a ritual. This is a faith statement
that we are putting out there because your words have power. >> Amen.
>> So, all grace abounds towards us. We have everything we need to
accomplish all that God has called us to do. We thank you
Lord for our land and we call it paid for in Jesus'
name. We thank you Lord for the provision to build all the
buildings needed for Movement Church, Movement Christian Academy and every work you
call us to do. We say yes to your plan and we
thank you for your grace to complete our assignment. We call this
done in Jesus name. Amen. Thank you Lord. So, if God has
put it on your heart that you want to start providing to
that, you know, through uh tithings, through offerings, there's a lot of
different ways that you can give. You can scan the QR code
um on the screen. It'll take you to our app. Or you
can uh tap the little circle um on the back of the
chairs that will also take you to our app. Or there's an
old school offering box in the back nailed to the wall that
you know, we don't really pass the the buckets around anymore. Um,
but you know, the the the main thing that God always puts
on my heart is test me in this area. Test me with
your finances. I always think about this because it's the one area
God tells you to test him on. And when you test him
on it, he is always faithful to provide. We were not tithing
when we first started. We actually had the very opposite mindset of,
oh, they just want to take all our money. But once we
started to open our eyes to, you remember I said broken moved
here. So we were lost and broken, we we found our way
into the, you know, the right mindset of what God wants to
do with your finances. So when you test him, when you start
to tithe and you start to provide offerings, he will always give
back. So when we finally started, it was like the next year,
I think both of us got promotions. Both of us got out
of cycle raises. We were getting bonuses left and right. Money was
just flowing into us. were like, "Oh, I don't know what to
do with all this." We didn't have any kids, so it was
pretty awesome at that point. We took a lot of international vacations.
Um, and we will again soon. Praise the Lord. But, you know,
and we we kept staying faithful. And I just got a promotion
just this last week. So, the Lord is good. He will always
provide for you. He will always open up the windows of heaven
and pour out his blessings onto you. So, I invite you to
say prayers with me in faith that if the Lord is putting
something on your heart to open that up and provide that to
the Lord through the church through, you know, it doesn't even always
have to be through the church. You can give in other ways
that show your love to of Jesus. So, you can show your
love to other people. So, I'm going to say a prayer over
the offerings and I invite you to say, you know, something else
with me. Say a prayer in your own heart and your own
words [music] that you know God will open up your mind to
the importance of tithing and providing offerings. Father God, I thank you
so much every day for how good you are. You are the
only one worthy of our praise, of our offerings, of our time,
of our tithing, of everything we have. It is all yours because
it was always yours. And you've just given it to us first
because you loved us. Just like children, you give us gifts and
blessings just like I give my children gifts and blessings because I
love them. Your love for us is just so much more so
much more powerful, [music] so much more generous. And so Lord, I
pray that you just help those around here that are questioning whether
tithing and offerings are a good thing or the right thing. You
just speak to them. You just give them knowledge. Give them wisdom.
give them something that shows your love and what you do with
this that it was all yours to begin with and we're just
giving back in thanks. So I thank you Lord for everybody here,
everyone that's tithing, everyone that's providing, everyone that's going to provide in
the future. I pray you open up the windows of heaven. Pour
out just blessing on blessing on blessing [music] on them so it's
so overwhelming to them that they can't help but provide more. not
just to the church but to everyone they interact with. They just
be just a beacon of offering and blessing to others so that
others can see your heart. In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
[music]
Hey movement parents, we've got some exciting news for you. The MC
kids parent newsletter is now available on the movement app. All you
have to do is open the app, tap on movement kids, and
it'll take you directly to the newsletter. Or if you're here in
service, you can simply tap your phone to the sticker on the
back of your chair, and it'll bring it up for you that
way. The parent newsletter has everything you need to keep you connected
and up to date with what your kids are learning each week.
You'll find an overview of our current series, details about what we're
teaching each Sunday, including a memory verse video that has hand motions
to go along with it, and then there are also some simple
ways that you can keep the conversation going at home throughout the
week as you disciple your kids together as a family. Also, if
you want a copy to save or to share, then you're able
to download that at the bottom of that screen. So, check it
out today and don't forget to turn on your app notifications so
you never miss an update or announcement. We're so excited to continue
partnering with you as your kids grow in their faith. >> Comment, >> share,
>> comment, >> share. >> Hey, Movement Church family. If you love what God is
doing here, help us share it. [music] So, I'm going to ask
you to take out your phone. Go ahead. You're not going to
get in trouble. I will wait.
If you have your phone, go to social media. I know you
have it. to go to Instagram or Facebook and take a [music]
second to like, comment, or share our most recent post. Every interaction
helps more people discover Jesus and experience what is happening here at
Movement Church. Let's not be the best kept secret here in Theina.
Help us spread the word.
>> [music]
>> Heat. Hey, Heat.
Amen. Praise the Lord. Well, who had a good time yesterday on
the 4th of July? Anybody blow anything up? >> Didn't blowing your fingers
up, did you? Everybody got your fingers and your toes and everything?
Well, as Josh mentioned, we just want to celebrate with you guys
what an amazing country that we live in. >> 250 years. I mean,
think about this. There's a lot. Think about the other nations uh
and countries on the planet. And they've been around a long time.
We've only been around 250 years. That's not very long at all.
But look at what God has done in only 250 years. >> Don't
make no mistake about it. This is the Lord's work in the
United States of America. The reason the United States of America is
so successful is because we are one nation under God. That's why
because we chose God. You there's a uh God chose the nation
of Israel to be his his people. But we as a people
chose God. We as a nation chose him. That is awesome. And
God, you know, we we share more gospel from the United States
than any other country combined on the planet. The gospel is being
spread all throughout the world from the United States of America. Amen.
We send out more missionaries than anybody else. We send out more
financial aid than anybody else. We send out more food than anybody
else. We are making this planet great. Amen. >> Make the planet great
again. Amen. [laughter] Well, praise God. I got a couple of dad
jokes for you today. >> Amen. These are good. I'm telling you, these
are really good. See, I asked my wife the other day, or
actually, she asked me. She said, "Did you see the dog bowl?"
She'd asked me if I've seen the dog bowl and I said,
"No, I didn't know that he did."
That'll catch on here in just a minute. My doctor uh I
told my doctor that I broke my arm in two places. He
told me to start avoiding those two places. [laughter] And this is
the Star Wars one. I got to throw a Star Wars one
every week this week. It's for the Star Wars group. If you
don't know Star Wars, then you won't have any idea what I'm
talking about. But what sound do Yoda's sheep make? They go by.
They go by. See, they laughed really hard. They go by. Yoda
was from Deoba. >> Anyway, I got it. >> You got it. Amen. Praise
God. Well, let's talk about something that we can all relate to.
Our covenant. >> Did you know that you have a covenant with Almighty
God? >> We're talking in this series about covenant living. And I believe
this is it's really the foundation of Christianity. It's really sad that
you don't hear more people talking about their covenant because the the the
the faith that we have in Jesus Christ is based on our
covenant with him. We started this series last week and I'm going
to review just for a minute talking about the scriptures uh about
this. Let's look at Ephesians chapter 2 and verse number 11. It
says, "Therefore remember that you once Gentiles in the flesh who are
called uncircumcision by what is called the circumcision made in the flesh
by hands that at that time you were without Christ." How many
of you are without Christ at some point in your life? That
would be all of us, right? At some point in our life,
we were without Christ. Uh we were without Christ, being aliens from
the commonwealth of Israel and strangers from the covenants of promise, having
no hope and without God in this world without knowing your covenant,
without knowing Jesus, not knowing the covenant that you had. It says
we were strangers. We were foreigners. We didn't know anything about this.
But look what it says. We jump down to verse number 13.
It says, "But now in Christ Jesus, you who are once far
off have been brought near by the blood of Christ." We sing
a lot about the blood. We sing a lot about the blood
of Christ. What's the blood of Christ mean? What's it all about?
We're going to be talking more about that this morning. Look at
verse 19. Now therefore, you are no longer strangers and foreigners. >> You
were, but now in Christ Jesus, you're no longer a stranger. Say,
"I'm no longer a stranger." no longer a stranger. >> I'm no longer
a foreigner. >> No longer a foreigner, >> but fellow citizens with the saints
and members of the household of God. So, we have a class
in our Bible college now. We're launching it in the fall and
we have a class on the blood covenant. I'm not going to
go into all of the details of that class. There's just so
much to talk about in your blood covenant. In this series, we're
really talking about how to live in it, which that is really
the most important thing. How to take advantage of and live in
your covenant. A covenant is the most sacred agreement you can enter
into with anybody. >> The Bible is a book of covenants, and covenants
have been in our history since the very beginning of time. There
were many covenants in the Bible. Matter of fact, you could go
all the way to the Garden of Eden, and there are signs
that there was a covenant there. We don't have any scripture on
that. But we do remember that remember Cain and Abel, Adam and
Eve's first two children. Remember there were they were what were they
doing? They were making sacrifices to God. And remember Cain got mad
at Abel because God accepted his sacrifice, didn't accept his. And so
he murdered his brother. >> But why were they sacrificing? Where did they
learn that? Where did that come from? That looks like something that
we would see in a covenant. We see covenants throughout scripture. We
see people entering into covenants together. You remember uh David and Jonathan
entered a covenant together. We see a covenant when Noah got off
the ark and God said, "I will never again flood uh destroy
this earth with water." Remember, he put his rainbow in in the
sky. You remember this? That was a covenant that God made. Not
all covenants are blood covenants. And all not all covenants are the
same. And so we see covenants throughout scripture in the Bible. You
know, Job had a covenant. Did you know that? The Bible doesn't
go into detail about Job's covenant, but the the few things that
we can see is remember whenever Satan was trying to go after
Job, what did God tell him? You can't take his life. Remember
that. So obviously, and Job was making sacrifices before that. So obviously
had a covenant with God. We don't know the nature of it.
We don't know what kind of covenant it was, but we know
that it was a lifepreserving covenant because God said, "You'll not take
his life." So, that's one of the big problems and challenges Christians
have today is we read the Bible and we're reading all these
things. We're reading in the book of Job. We're reading about the
children of Israel and all the things that they went through and
we don't have a covenant mindset. And so, we don't understand what
was going on. You cannot try to live your life under the
covenant that Job was in. you you you can't it doesn't fit
what what we belong to a what the Bible calls a new
covenant. >> Amen. And so we're going to look at that today and
we're going to look at this new covenant God cut with a
man by the name of Abraham. God cut a covenant with a
man named Abraham. Of course, we know that this was a everlasting
covenant. We know that this was a blood covenant. We know that
this is the most sacred covenant that you could cut with anybody.
And God entered into a covenant with man. Now, let me just
go ahead and tell you something. God is really smart. >> If you
hadn't figured that out yet, you'll realize the more you learn about
his word, you're like, God is like beyond brilliant, right? Like he
he's working 10, 12, hundred things right here when he's cutting a
covenant with Abraham. There's a lot of things that he's working right
now. He enters into this covenant with Abraham. Here's the problem. The
problem is that God is perfect. God's word is perfect. His law
is perfect. And so God is perfect. And when God states what
he's going to do in his covenant, he's going to do it.
When God says something, he's going to do it. Look at this
scripture in Psalms 89:34. My covenant I will not break.
Is God going to break his covenant? My covenant I will not
break nor alter the word that has come out of my lips.
So in other words, if God promised you something in this covenant,
he gonna do it. >> He's going to do it. You can take
him at his word. >> If you said it, I'll believe it. >> Did
we just sing that? If he said it, I'll believe it. But
you do you realize how many people do not believe God when
he says something. And Christians seem to struggle when God tells us
something. When he makes us the promise, we're like, I don't know
if I can believe that or not. Well, think about this. The
common contract that you have today is based off of a covenant,
right? Except it's not in blood. You sign your name these days
in our culture. You just sign your name and say, "Yeah, that
was me and I I signed my name." You go to You
go to buy a house, you sign all this paperwork and you
enter into a contractual agreement to buy this house. Or you go
to a car dealership to buy a car and you sign the
paper and you enter into a contract to to buy this car
and nobody's ever shocked when they bring you the car. Have you
ever been shocked? You go into a car dealership to buy a
car and then you're like, "Boy, I just hope they bring that
car around. I hope I get to have this car. I just
don't, man. I just I know I just signed a paperwork, but
I'm just not sure." You got more faith in a silly little
contract to buy a car than we do in the word of
God. >> You believe the salesman, >> a car salesman, and we know they
don't always tell us the truth. and you fully have full confidence
that they are going to give you the car that you just
signed for. >> Am I right about it? >> We We do this all
the time in our culture and and we don't think anything about
it. It It just happens, right? You go to this McDonald's to
buy you a cheeseburger and you pay for that cheeseburger first and
you're you're not even worried if they're going to bring it to
you or not. You're not even worried. Well, you might need to
be worried, but no, you shouldn't be worried about that. You're not
you you just you just expect because they said they're going to
bring you a cheeseburger. I paid for it. So, it's coming. The
French fries are coming. I just go sit down and relax and
drink my get my little Coke ready and and you're just relaxing
with your family and talking and not even worried about it because
you know it's coming because you got a promise, right? And and
we have more confidence in that than we do God's word. >> And
God's the one that said, "My covenant I will not break." So
if God says something in his covenant when he stated what he
will do in his covenant, he will absolutely do that. >> Every time.
I said every time. And he will not deviate from that. He
will always do what his word says. >> Now some people misquote God
a little bit or say things about God that are not true.
And they'll say something like this. God can do anything he wants.
He's God. No, he can't. I said, "No, he can't." >> You say,
"Pastor, that sounds wrong. That sounds so unreligious." I know. >> But God
can't just do whatever he wants. He's going to do what he
promised. >> Do you see the difference? He's going to do what he
said he's going to do. It does. He He He follows his
word. So, if he said it, he's going to do it. Yeah,
>> you can take him at his word. Amen. Why? Because we are
in a covenant with God >> and he said, "My covenant I will
not break." But here's the problem. When he entered into a covenant
with Abraham, we know we're not perfect. >> None of us are perfect.
We all have flaws. And he entered into a covenant agreement with
a man who was fallible. A man who was going to make
mistakes. a man who was going to break the covenant and every
generation after him was going to break the covenant. There's a problem
here, right? God's not going to break the covenant. He said, "I'm
not going to break my if I said it, I'm going to do
it." And God is perfect and he's all powerful and all. And
he can do that. He's going to hold up his end. But
by entering into a covenant with Abraham, God put provisions in place
ahead of time so that we could live in our covenant. Let's
read about it. We're going to read some scripture today that most
people just read over or when you read it, you don't know
anything about it because it's all about your covenant. But let's read
here what God did, the provision he put in place so that
man wouldn't have to die. Because violating the covenant, you know, there
was a blessing associated with following God's law and then there was
cursings associated with it leading up to death. And there was many
things that that that that led to death. If you broke the covenant,
you deserve to die. And and people read these kind of things
in the Old Testament. They're like, "Man, God's so harsh. God's so
mean. God is not mean at all. >> If you didn't make your
car payment and they came repossessed it, you wouldn't say, "Well, they're
so mean. You entered into a contract to pay for that car,
you didn't pay for it for three months, so they showed up
at your door and said, "Give me the car." It wasn't personal.
It wasn't because they didn't like you. It's because you violated the
contract. And that's what you're seeing throughout the Old Testament. You're seeing
the children of Israel following the Lord. Then they violated the covenant.
bad things began to happen. But God put provisions in place for
that. Let's read about it. Leviticus chapter 16 and verse 5. It
says, "And he shall take from the congregation of the children of
Israel two kinds of the goats as a sin offering and one
ram as a burnt offering. Aaron, who was the high priest, by
the way, Aaron shall offer the bull as a sin offering, which
is for himself, and make atonement. Say, atonement. >> Is the big Bible
word right here. Atonement. Make atonement for himself and for his house.
He shall take two goats and present them before the Lord at
the door of the tabernacle of meeting. Then Aaron shall cast lots
for the two goats. One lot for the Lord and the other
lot for the scapegoat. You ever hear that term before? Scapegoat. Wonder
where it comes from. Comes from the Bible. It comes from covenant
language. Can you just It's just shocking to me how much covenant
language and covenant practice are in our culture and nobody knows. Have
you ever used the term scapegoat? So it says here that there's
going to be a scapegoat. What happens to the scapegoat here and
the other escape goat? And Aaron shall bring the goat on which
the Lord's lot fell and offer it as a sin offering. But
the goat on which the lot fell to be the scapegoat shall
be presented alive before the Lord to make atonement upon it and
to let it go as the scapegoat into the wilderness. Well, we
know what a scapegoat is, right? The scapegoat's the one that takes
the blame. And so there were two goats that they would bring.
And they would bring a bull. Aaron would bring a bull. And
this was happening once a year. This is known as the day
of atonement. And this day of atonement, what Aaron, the high priest,
was supposed to do is sacrifice the bull. Sacrifice one of the
goats as an offering. It's a sin offering to the Lord. The
other one would be the scapegoat. And what Aaron would do is
he would pronounce the sins of Israel over the scapegoat and then
send the scapegoat away. Does that sound familiar to anybody? Anything you
know about the New Testament? All of your sin was put on
Jesus. >> Jesus was your scapegoat. >> Amen. >> And so this would happen throughout
scripture. Now look at this verse number 16. So he shall make
atonement. There it is again. Atonement for the holy place because of
the uncleanliness of the children of Israel and because of their transgressions,
for all their sins. So he shall do for the tabernacle of
meeting which remains among them in the midst of their uncleanness. There
shall be no man in the tabernacle of meeting when he goes
into it and makes atonement in the holy place until he comes
out that he may make atonement for himself and for his household
and for all the assembly of Israel. And he shall go out
to the altar that is before the Lord and make atonement for
it, and shall take some of the blood of the bull and
some of the blood of the goat. These are the ones that
were sacrificed. And put it on the horns of the altar all
around. And he shall sprinkle some of the blood on it with
the finger seven times. Cleanse it, consecrate it from the uncleanness of
the children of Israel. So this is the day of atonement. God
gave specific instructions to them. Specific instructions. Why? Because he knew that
man was going to violate the covenant. So entering into a covenant
with man, man's going to have to die. But God put provisions
in place so we didn't have to die. He'll take an animal
being sacrificed in ourstead. and we'll put we'll put the sins of
the people on the scapegoat and we'll sacrifice the blood of an
animal to atone for the sins of the people. You know what
this is? This is like kicking the can down the road. You
know that expression, I'm just kicking the can down the road. This
is this is not dealing with the issue immediately, not dealing with
this sin issue, but covering it. To atone for means to cover.
It means to cover. And so the sin would be covered by
the blood of these animals and the sins. And this would happen
on the day of atonement. Once per year, the high priest would
go in and do this and sprinkle the blood. He would go
into the holy of holies in the temple of God and sprinkle
this blood. And God gave him specific instructions about it. Well, if
you go read all of Leviticus, you'll see that there were daily
sacrifices that had to be made. There were weekly sacrifices that had
to be made. There were monthly sacrifices and there were special days
where they sacrificed and then there was the day of atonement. Day
after day after day sacrifice I mean I I did the math
on this over,200 animals a year dying being sacrificed over 1,200 a
year because of all of the sin. So day after day after
day they were reminded that they were sinful. They were reminded that
they had to have this animal sacrificed in mystead because I have
not lived up to God's standard. I have not followed God's covenant.
Day after day after day, there was the reminder of sin. But
God put this provision in place so man doesn't have to die.
Yet. I said yet. >> We're kicking the can down the road here.
And so we're kicking the can down the road. Kicking the can
down the road. And this did not do away with the sin.
It was simply covering. Atonement means to cover. Let me tell you
something. The blood of Jesus does not atone for your sins. >> It
doesn't sound like that's a good religious saying, but it's true. Because
God Jesus blood did not cover your sin. He washed your sin
away. >> Amen. >> So this is what God did in his covenant with
Abraham. so that we wouldn't have to die. So that Abraham wouldn't
have to die. His kids wouldn't have to die. So when they
broke the covenant, there were provisions in place. Here's what I want
you to see. God was lenient on their side of the covenant.
He wasn't on his. Oh, come on, somebody. It wasn't like
God said, "Okay, this is what we're gonna do." When you brought
said, "Okay, this is what we're gonna do. when you break the
covenant, you can do all these sacrifices and this will atone for
the sins and we'll just kick the can down the road and
we're not going to personally hold you accountable for that sin. We're
going to put it on the goat. We're going to sacrifice the bull.
And he put all this in place so that he would be
lenient on them so it wouldn't cost them their life. God didn't
do that for himself. He said, "My covenant I will not break.
I will not violate what I said." If God were to do
that, the whole universe should be ripped apart because the Bible says
that his word is holding it all together right now. If he
violated his covenant, if he violated his word, nothing would exist anymore.
So God was lenient on our side of the covenant. He's not
on his. You can in fact take him at his word. Amen.
>> He will not violate his covenant. >> When he promises you something in
the word of God, can you believe it? I don't know, pastor.
I just can't seem to believe this. I can't seem I just
can't seem to go there. Do you not know you have a
covenant with God? >> Do you not know that God will not violate
his covenant? And if he said it, he's going to do it.
>> You're just supposed to believe it. Well, how come I don't see
these things in my life? because we haven't believed it. >> Because we
don't believe his word, because we don't believe his promises. We don't
believe in his covenant. >> Amen. So, he put this provision in place
like kicking the can down the road like this sin issue. Man's
blood would not be shed for this. He entered into this covenant
and man should have died a long time ago. But this provision
was put in place, these animal sacrifices so that man did not
have to pay the punishment for that sin. But look at what
happened here in Hebrews chapter 8 verse number one. You only can
kick the can down the roads for so long. It's like kind
of like borrowing money to pay for money you borrowed, right? You
borrow money and then you borrow money to pay for that. Then
you borrow money to pay that one off. Then you borrow money
and you can only do that for so long. And eventually someone's
going to have to pay, right? You can't just keep borrowing and
borrowing and borrowing to pay off the other debt. At some point
the debt's going to have to be paid. And so at some
point this debt was going to have to be paid. At some
point man would have to pay for violating the covenant. Anybody know
what happened with the man who had to pay for that? It
was Jesus. So, we're gonna get some inside scoop now into what
Jesus did. Most Christians only believe Jesus came to the earth, died
on the cross for their sins, okay? And we're get to go
to heaven. That's about as far as they go. But Hebrews is
an amazing book of the Bible because Hebrews gives us the inside
scoop on what Jesus actually did. Look at verse number one, Hebrews
8. Now this um this is the main point of the things
we are saying. We have such a high priest who is seated
at the right hand of the throne of the ma in the
majesty in the heavens. Who is that? That's Jesus. Jesus is your
high priest. Jesus is your high priest under our new covenant. Jesus
is our high priest. Look at verse number two. a minister of
the sanctuary and of the true tabernacle which the Lord erected and
not a man.
For every high priest is appointed to offer both gifts and sacrifices.
Therefore, it is necessary that this one also have something to offer.
For if if he were on earth, that tells you he's not
on the earth right now. If he were on the earth, he
would not be a priest since there are priests who offer the
gifts according to the law, who serve the copy and shadow of
the heavenly things. We're talking about a temple in heaven. We're talking
about Jesus in heaven being your high priest and my high priest.
Why do you think God was so specific when he told them
how to build the temple? You know, you read these things in
the Bible and you're just like, "This is just boring. I just
don't know why we go in all these details of why we
got to be." Have you read through this? Like he when he
told him to build the temple, he was so specific. It was
down to every last little detail. He called it out and measured
this, build it this size. What was he doing? He was creating,
he was having them build on the earth an exact replica of
the temple that's in heaven. And it's very clear from scripture. We'll
we'll continue to see this. Who serve as a copy and a
shadow of the heavenly things as Moses was divinely instructed when he
was about to make the tabernacle. For he said, "See that you
make all things according to the pattern shown you on the mountain."
This is why he gave him the pattern because you're going to
build a temple on the earth exactly like the one up here.
Now, let's look what he says in verse number uh skip over
to Hebrews 9:6. Now, when these things had thus uh prepared, the
priest always went into the first part of the tabernacle performing the
services, but into the second part the high priest went alone once
a year. This is talking exactly about the day of atonement once
a year when the high priest would go into the holy of
holies. We're we're reading about it here in the New Testament right
here in the book of Hebrews. We're reading about this moment we
read about in Leviticus where the high priest would go in. He
would he would cast the lot and one goat would be the
scapegoat. The other one would be slaughtered, bull be slaughtered, and he
would sprinkle the blood the blood over and and it would atone
for the sins of the people. What we just read about he's
talking about right here. And he said the high priest went alone
once a year, not without blood. He had to go in there
with blood, not without blood, which offered for himself and for the
people sins committed in ignorance. The Holy Spirit indicating this that the
way into the holiest of all was not yet made manifest while
the first tabernacle was still standing.
Now let's look at verse 11. But Christ say Christ. >> Christ. >> Christ
came as what? >> High priest. Remember we said he is your high
priest. As high priest of the good things to come with the
greater and more perfect tabernacle not made with hands. Which one we
talking about? We're not talking about the one on the earth. We're
talking about the heavenly tabernacle.
that is not of this creation. Not listen to me now. Oh,
this is going to set some of you free. Not with the
blood of goats and calves, >> but with his own blood. >> With his
own blood, he entered into the most holy place once and for
all. >> Once and for all. What does that mean? That means this
doesn't have to happen once a year. That means this doesn't have
to happen every day, every week, every month on the Jewish festival
days and in the day of atonement. This this means that this
is once and for all, >> once and for all with his own
blood, having obtained eternal redemption. For if the blood of bulls and
goats, and the ashes of a hepher, sprinkling the unclean, sanctifies for
the purifying of the flesh, how much more, how much more shall
the blood of Christ, who through the eternal spirit offered himself without
spot to God, cleanse your conscience from dead works to serve a
living God. >> What What are we seeing here? What is this? This
is what we're seeing is Jesus after he died on the cross
and he ascended into heaven, he brought his blood and he entered
into the holy of holies, the most holy place in the tabernacle
of heaven and he did the exact same sacrifice that Aaron the
priest, the high priest would do, except he did it with his
own blood. And the blood of a goat. This was much more
powerful than the blood of a goat or a bull because this
blood did not atone for the sins. It was washing the sins
away. >> That's why it says once and for all. >> Once and for
all. Amen. >> What does this mean to us? This means that Jesus
is not going daily in the temple and offering his blood. >> He's
not doing this every day. He's not doing this every week. Some
people teach that. They say, "Well, Jesus has got to go in
because I sin. Tomorrow, Jesus has got to go back in." No,
he did it once and for all. Say, "Once and for all."
>> Once and for all. >> He did it once and for all. >> And
he did it for every single person that would ever live on
planet Earth. Amen. >> What does this mean for us? What does this
mean for us now? How do we how do we take advantage
of this in our covenant now? How does this affect the way
we live? Here's the thing I want to tell you. You and
I don't have to live with a sin conscience.
>> You and I don't have to live like they did under the
old covenant. >> Daily reminded of you're a failure, reminded of your sin,
reminded of how many times you screwed up and we've got to
do sacrifice after. And it was a daily reminder, a weekly reminder,
a yearly reminder. No longer do you have to live that way.
>> Do you realize that Christians all over the planet have fallen for
the devil's lies and trap and every day they wake up feeling
condemned. They feel like they're under condemnation. They feel like, "Oh, why?
Because they've sinned. Because they messed up. Oh, I messed up again.
Oh, I messed up again and again and again." And the devil's
like, "Yeah, you dirty, rotten sinner. You're nothing but a sinner." And
people have said it. I'm just an old sinner. No, you're not.
>> I said, "No, you're not." >> Because the blood of Jesus has done
once. Say once and for all. >> Oh, you're not you're not sure
now because we're talking about my sin now.
>> See, here's here's the problem. Christians have had bad teaching on this
and they've been taught that every time you sin now Jesus has
got to go do something for you. >> You've got to repent of
it. Jesus got to sprinkle the blood again. Got to go into
the Holy of Holies. Or they don't even know what it means.
They just believe that's the way it is. I've got to I've
got to confess my sin. Jesus has got to once again forgive
me of my sins and all these kind of things. And then
and then and and this is why listen to me now. This
is why the erroneous teaching that if someone commits suicide, they're going
to hell. That's where it comes from. >> And I just felt impressed
of the spirit to tell you today that that's not true. >> The
reason they teach that is because if someone commits suicide, the very
last act on this earth was to kill somebody themselves. And they
didn't have time to repent, >> right? Didn't have time to repent. So,
you must be going to hell. >> Is that what we're seeing from
scripture? >> That that's where that teaching comes from. >> Well, it's not just
suicide. What if you yelled at your wife and then stepped out
in front of a car and got run over by a car?
What if you sinned, but it wasn't as bad, right? We categorize
these things, but it wasn't that bad. But what if, but what
if your little white lie or your little sin happened right before
you die? And you know how many people sin before they die
>> or they're sinning when they die. >> This happens all the time. >> It's
not just people who are committing suicide. It happens all the time.
So, well, pastor, how can I go to heaven if if I've
committed sin and I haven't asked forgiveness for it? Because the blood
of Jesus
>> has already paid the price for your sin once and for all.
Say, "Once and for all." >> And for all. >> Once and for all.
What does that mean? He doesn't have to do it again. >> Once
and for all. Amen. >> We're going to see some more scripture about
this. Hebrews 10, chapter 10. I'm fired up about this. >> You need
to know how to live in your covenant. And you need to
stop listening to the lies of the devil bringing condemnation on you
because you screw up. God had a plan. Oh, God is so
good. >> Don't be Don't be talking bad about my God >> saying how
he wants you sick. He wants you broke. He wants you depressed.
He planned this a long time ago. >> He He put these sacrifices
in place, the whole priesthood and all of this so man wouldn't
be punished for their sin. And then he sent Jesus to pay
the price for your sin so you wouldn't have to pay it.
So the price would be paid. Don't tell me God is bad.
>> He's a good God. >> He loves you. >> I mean, he could have
just been like, "You know what? I'm tired of them. Thump, >> that's
all of us. >> Aren't you glad you're not God or I'm not
God? They just keep sinning. Get rid of them. Our patience have
been gone, right? God is so merciful. His mercy, the Bible says,
>> endures >> forever. >> He's so merciful. He's so loving and kind.
He put no provision in place if he screwed up. But for
us, he got all these provisions in place. And then he sent
Jesus. So he knew this man will not violate the covenant. >> And
he knew that this man would live a perfect sinless life. And
then they turned around and killed him for it. fell right into
God's master plan trap. The Bible says that that that the devil
would have known what this was, but he's too stupid. >> God's he's
like 10, 15, 150 steps ahead of him. >> And then it's only
after the fact he was like, "Maybe we shouldn't have killed Jesus
because now the blood of Jesus has paid for all of these
people's sins.
>> Now I'm going to have to lie." >> And he's okay with that.
And how many people do you know living living this way under
the condemnation of sin? The devil's like, "Yeah, look at you. Yeah,
you can't do anything for God. Look at your sin. Look at
how many times you messed up." Even after you're a Christian, look
how many times you messed up. What kind of Christian are you?
The Bible says once and for all. Say once and for all.
>> Once and for all. >> I'll read this. Hebrews 10:10. Listen to this.
But that the but that will I'm sorry. By that will, I
get so stirred up. I can't even read it. By that will,
we have been sanctified through the offering of the body of Jesus
Christ.
>> Once for all. >> Oh man, here it is again. You know, when
the Bible repeats something, he's trying to make a point. Yeah. >> And
every priest stands ministering daily and offering repeatedly the same sacrifices which
can never say never >> take away sins. All those sacrifices
did not take away the sin. It atoned for it. >> There's been
horrible teaching in the church that said Jesus blood atoned for your
sin. It did not.
>> I got one amen. See, it just sounds bad, right? You're like,
I can't believe he said that. Jesus, let's say it again. Jesus
blood did not atone for your sin. >> It did not cover your
sin. It did not put it on a goat and send it
running away into the wilderness. It washed it away. >> It's gone. >> Jesus
was the scapegoat. It was put on him and he walked into
the holy of holies with his own blood. The blood of a
man >> and sprinkled it on the mercy seat. He's He did the
exact same thing except it was with a man's blood. Now the
price has been paid.
>> You got to know your covenant >> once and for all. Every priest
stands ministering daily and offering repeatedly the same sacrifices which can never
take away sins. But this man after he had offered one sacrifice
for sins >> forever.
[laughter] >> Am I the only one stirred up about this >> one sacrifice?
>> Thank God we don't have to do this every day. Thank God
I don't have if I was the h Oh my goodness. I
retired. >> I quit. Are you kid? That was a lot of work.
>> A lot of bulls, a lot of calves, a lot of goats.
I mean, that's just a that's bloody
gross, right? I mean, that's just it was just think about how
much and it was a constant constant reminder. You're still a sinner.
You're still a sinner. You're still a sinner. You still got sin
in your life. We don't have to do that. Why? Because just
this man had offered one sacrifice for sins forever. >> I said forever.
>> Do I need to define this word for you guys? >> Forever means
>> for all time. >> He don't have to do it again. >> If if
this was not the case, Jesus would have to come back to
the earth. He would have to die again. And he would have
to come back to the Holy of Holies and sprinkle more blood.
And then Jason sinned again. Here we go. Come back Jesus and
do it again. And Jesus comes back to the earth again. The
sinless son of God dies again. Goes in again and and day.
And Jesus doesn't have to do this every day. You need to
know what covenant you're living under. >> You need to know that the
blood of a man was what was required. This is what was
required by the covenant because man had sinned. Man's blood had to
be shed. >> But God is so merciful. He sent his son. Isn't
that awesome? >> That's amazing. It says once and for all for the
sins forever, sat down at the right hand of God from that
time waiting till his enemies are made his foottool. For by one
offering he has perfected forever those who are being sanctified. one offering.
>> Man, what an offering. >> What an offering that was by his own
blood. Now, here's the question. Every Christian deals with every Christians uh
I shouldn't say every there's a lot of people have no idea
what we just went through. No idea that the blood of Jesus
has washed them clean. They think it's atonement or they think that
this is something that repeatedly has to be done repeatedly. Repeatedly. He
doesn't have to do this all the time. He paid for your
sins, past, present, and future. Not just yours, but every person that
would ever live. >> Once and for all. >> Remember, we said it multiple
times. Once and for all. Once and for all. Once and for
all. Once and for all. >> We got to get it through our
thick skull. >> You don't have to live under condemnation because you sinned.
>> You don't. >> You can if you listen to the lies of the
devil. every time you screw up, he'll tell you that. You'll be
like, "Ah." So, what do we do? Here's here's the problem. Here's
how here's where Christians are. Christians are like, "Okay, pastor, I get
you, but now that I'm born again and I sin, what now?"
See, you don't know your covenant. You don't realize that he did
it once and for all. It wasn't just before you were born
again, all those sins. It was all of your sins forever. >> All
of them. >> Yeah. >> Which leads people to think, well, okay, that means
I can sin as much as I want >> because they're all covered
under the blood of Jesus and I can sin as much as
I want. Can you? >> What if you sinned a hundred times? You still
going to heaven?
>> Yes. No. I don't know. Trick question time. What if you sinned
a thousand times? What if you are like going to make it
a mission after I'm born again? I'm going to sin as much
as I can. See if I can still make it.
What would that be? We gonna make it. Tim's like, "You're on
thin ice." [laughter] Is it once and for all or once and
for all? >> You You're okay with Once and for all just a
minute ago, but when I started putting numbers on it, you're like,
"I don't know about you now, pastor. I don't know. You just
gonna keep on sinning. You shouldn't want to sin anymore >> as a
believer, as a Christian. >> You shouldn't want to, but we do. We
mess up. We make mistakes, right? What happens now? Is that is
that sin not covered under the blood of Jesus? No. With sacrifices
once and for all, that sin's covered as well. Well, why can't
I just sin as much as I want? Why can't Well, what
we just read, let me read it again to you. It says,
"But this man, after he had offered one sacrifice for sin forever,
sat down at the right hand of God from that time waiting."
What's he waiting for? He's waiting till his enemies are made his
foottool. Drop the mic.
>> He's waiting for his enemies. And this word foottool is a very
interesting word. When when you start digging into what this actually means,
we know what a foottool is. My my grandmother was 4 foot
six and she had a foot stool at church and she used
to sit on the front row and uh because you know her
feet would not touch the ground. That's why she had a foot
stool. So she had this little this little foottool here and she
would put her feet on it because they they weren't long enough
to reach the ground. That's a foottool, right? It is, but it
has more meaning than that. This term foottool is actually has the
meaning more of not just something you put your feet on, but
the idea of conquest and conquering. Like when someone would defeat an
army, they would come and they would put their foot right on
the person's neck. It was a sign of conquest. It was a
sign of conquering them. They were now their foottool. They put their
foot right there on their neck and just stood and just stood
there. He's waiting till his enemies are made his foottool. Well, who
are the enemies? Well, we know the devil's an enemy. The Bible
says death is an enemy. There are many enemies, right? So, whose
responsibility now is it to do these things?
Living under our new covenant, not hindered by sin any longer? Sin
should not stop you from doing what God's called you to do.
Sin should not stop you from being the person God's called you
to be. Now all that's been done away with. Jesus took care
of all that. Once and for all. We said, "Yay, pastor. Once
and for all. Once and for all." And so now all that
all those excuses are gone. You don't have to sacrifice the day.
It's all over. But pastor, I screwed up. Shut your mouth.
>> Your job now is to do the work of God on the
earth. Your job is to make sure his enemies are made his
foottool. >> Your job is to take the word of God. So, so
why could I sin as much as I want? Why do you
want to? That's not our purpose. >> It's not our purpose. >> And if
you want to sin that much, I would question, are you saved?
Do you love Jesus? Because the closer you get to Jesus, the
more you don't want to sin. >> Doesn't mean you're perfect. You still
gonna screw up. But the but the more you're you turn your
heart towards him, you don't want to do that any longer. I'll
use this example as we close. Angela and I took a couple
to dinner one night and and uh it was family members long
time ago. And you know when you take someone out to dinner
and you're going to pay for the meal and it's understood upfront,
what do you not do? You don't order everything on the menu,
right? And we took this couple out and and they found out
we were buying and man it was the they ordered the Admiral's
Feast. It was at Red Lobster back in the day. Admiral's Feast,
which was the most expensive thing on the menu. And not just
one Admiral's Feast, two. And then they ordered appetizers. And then after
it was all over, they wanted >> Have you been there? And I'm
sitting there going, "Well, just because I'm paying doesn't mean I wanted
you to do all that." And I really feel like that's kind
of how Jesus is. I really feel like that's kind of the
heart behind the sin issue. Yes, all those sins are paid for,
but he's like, "I don't want you to do that. >> I didn't
pay for all your sins so you could just keep on sinning
all you want."
>> What do we do now? Let's read it here in 1 John
chapter uh 1 verse 8. If we say that we have no
sin, we deceive ourselves.
>> Well, what this is saying is there's still sin. We still have
sin, right? We still sin. But having sin in your life does
not make you a sinner. >> Doesn't change your identity in Christ at
all. >> You are washed clean by the blood of Jesus. Even though
you've got sin now, there's obviously there's sin. We mess up. So
if we say we have no sin, we deceive ourselves. Don't get
prideful and say, "I going to sin now because of Jesus." No,
you're still messing up. >> And the truth is not in us. If
we confess our sin, he is faithful and just to forgive us
our sins and to cleanse us from all unrighteousness. >> And you see
that see there, pastor, you got to confess your sins or you're
not going to be cleansed of them. That's where they get it.
But you know what? We got to go back to what with
the basics that we've learned. When you got born again, what part
of you got born again? What part of you? Your spirit was
born again. The real you on the inside was born again. Washed
clean by the blood of Jesus. And out came the old man.
In came the new man. And by the way, the Holy Spirit
came with him. >> And now you got the spirit of God on
the inside of you as a Christian. And the Bible says that
you were sealed. Nothing's breaking that seal. >> So when you sin after
you're born again, it's still bad for you. I'm not saying it's
good for you. I Jesus has already paid the price for it.
The blood of Jesus washes you clean from it in your spirit.
But how many of you know my soul was not born again?
I had someone cut me off in traffic yesterday. >> I found out
real quick my soul was not born again. because I was having
thoughts of things I wanted to do to him. >> That wasn't godly
thoughts. >> I didn't let them come out of my mouth, but I
think I said, what did I say? I said something. It was
I mean, it wasn't positive. I'll just say that. I wasn't cussing
or nothing, but it was bad. I mean, it wasn't good. My
soul's not born again. I have and I have a physical body
that's not been born again. >> So, when we sin after we're a
Christian, you're still going to heaven. Your salvation is not in question.
If someone were to commit suicide, their spirit is sealed up. They're
still going to heaven. >> If they sin before they die and they
don't confess it, they're still going to heaven. What I'm saying is
this is not a salvation issue, >> but it is an issue in
your soul and it is an issue in your physical body. When
you sin as a New Testament born again Christian, you open your
physical body and your soul, your mind up to the devil >> and
you allow him to come in and do what he wants to
do. Well, think about it. How many Christians do you know messed
up in their mind? Physical bodies are suffering.
Learn how to live in your covenant. When you violate the covenant,
when you sin as a New Testament Christian, what do you do?
The Bible says, "Confess your sin." What do you do? You You
agree with God. What I did was wrong. >> That's what a confession
is. I'm in agreement. I'm going to say what he said. He
said it's wrong. I say it's wrong. I confess that, God, that
was wrong. Thank you for Thank you for for paying the price
for that. But when I release that to God and acknowledge that
to God, it washes me clean. My soul, my physical body is
no longer a prey of the enemy. >> Oh, this explains a little
bit, doesn't it? >> What about when we just hang on to these
things and we sin and we just hang on to that sin?
What does it do? It opens us up to attack from the
enemy. Doesn't mean I'm not going to heaven. Doesn't mean I'm not
saved. See, you don't have to live with a sin conscience any
longer. You don't have to live your life daily with this constant
bombarding. Ah, I just can't. I just can't. What you need to
do is learn how to live in your covenant. Learn that Jesus
has paid the price once and for all. We said for all
eternity, it says and his covenant is with us. Well, I'm not
Abraham's seed. Well, the Bible says that those of us who have
accepted in Galatians 3, we say this all the time, but this
is covenant language. In Galatians 3, it says because you accepted Jesus
as your savior and you're now in Christ, you are now Abraham's
seed. >> Seed and hes according to the promise. You're
in the covenant. Congratulations. >> Your sin gone.
What if I keep sinning? You better You need to stop. You
need to stop it. Quit. You're opening yourself up to attack from
the enemy. >> And why do you want to in the first place?
I don't know about you, I want to live my life for
the Lord. Amen. >> Let's all bow our heads today. Thank you, Jesus.
I believe there's people here today that you've been bombarded with these
thoughts, this condemnation of sin because you keep messing up. You keep
messing up. But it's like rehearsing this over and over in your
mind. The Lord wanted me to tell you today that you do
not have to live this way any longer. You don't have to
live under that condemnation any longer. Those sins have been washed by
the blood once and for all. He said, "You don't have to
live that way. You don't have to be this way. You don't
have to allow the devil to constantly bring it up." Well, pastor,
what do I do when he does? You remind him of the
blood of Jesus. You remind him that your sins are paid for.
You remind him that you have a covenant with almighty God. Father,
in the name of Jesus, I thank you. Thank you for your
covenant. Thank you that our sins are forgiven. They've been washed away.
They are gone. They have been sent on the scapegoat and they
are they are eradicated from our lives. Thank you Lord the price
has been paid once and for all. That the blood of Jesus
was enough. And I thank you Lord that we can now live
without the sin conscience without the constant reminders of our failures and
our flaws. But Lord we can lean into our covenant and our
covenant promises and declare say what you say about us. We can
trust what you say and we can lean on your word and
stand on our covenant promises. Thank you, Lord, for setting us free
from sin. Thank you, Lord, that we don't have to be condemned.
Thank you, Lord, that we don't have to live that way any
longer in the name of Jesus. Amen. Amen. Thank you, Lord. If
you need prayer today, I want you to come forward after the
service. If you've been tormented by this, I I feel like today
there's been people that have been just so tormented by this sin
issue. It's really bothered you. And I believe today the Lord is
opening your eyes and setting you free. Amen. Amen. If you need
prayer, come forward after the service. We love you guys. Have a
great week this week. God bless you. And we'll see you next
Sunday.